<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Zomboid Modeling Docs</title>
    <link>https://trynaeat.github.io/zomboid-modeling-docs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Zomboid Modeling Docs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 15:22:44 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trynaeat.github.io/zomboid-modeling-docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Files</title>
      <link>https://trynaeat.github.io/zomboid-modeling-docs/animation/files/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 15:22:44 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trynaeat.github.io/zomboid-modeling-docs/animation/files/</guid>
      <description>The following files are used as a starting template to create animations for Project Zomboid. They contain the armature along with a character mesh which you can use to start animating.
The .fbx file was grabbed from the Project Zomboid official discord and is a generic file you should be able to use in the modeling software of your choice.
The .blend file is a slight tweak of the .fbx file to give an instant start template if you&amp;rsquo;re working with Blender.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started</title>
      <link>https://trynaeat.github.io/zomboid-modeling-docs/animation/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 15:22:44 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trynaeat.github.io/zomboid-modeling-docs/animation/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>The following guide will assume you&amp;rsquo;re using Blender 3.1, although the .fbx file on the previous page can be used in pretty much any software of your choice.
First, download the .blend file from the Files page.
Open it up in blender. You&amp;rsquo;ll see a male character mesh and matching armature. From this you can start animating! If you&amp;rsquo;re completely new to animating, there are tons of guides out there for Blender on youtube.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exporting</title>
      <link>https://trynaeat.github.io/zomboid-modeling-docs/animation/exporting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 15:22:44 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trynaeat.github.io/zomboid-modeling-docs/animation/exporting/</guid>
      <description>Zomboid supports the .fbx and .x formats for models/animations. Since .fbx is a much newer and more flexible format supported by many tools, I suggest using .fbx at all times.
To export your animation, first select everything in the scene (that means the armature AND Body mesh). Now, there are a couple of options for how you want your action exported&amp;hellip;
Export NLA You can push the actions you want to NLA strips, then in the export settings choose to export NLA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Putting Your Animation in Project Zomboid</title>
      <link>https://trynaeat.github.io/zomboid-modeling-docs/animation/placing-in-pz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 15:22:44 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trynaeat.github.io/zomboid-modeling-docs/animation/placing-in-pz/</guid>
      <description>In your mod&amp;rsquo;s folder, if you don&amp;rsquo;t yet have a directory called anims_X, create one. Creat a subfolder called Bob, then place your .fbx file into it.
Now, the first thing I like to do is make sure that my base animation is getting loaded correctly by the game. Launch your game in debug mode (add -debug to launch options in steam), load up a single player game and then open up the debug menu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Animation Sets</title>
      <link>https://trynaeat.github.io/zomboid-modeling-docs/animation/animation-sets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 15:22:44 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trynaeat.github.io/zomboid-modeling-docs/animation/animation-sets/</guid>
      <description>The next thing you need to do is create your animation sets. These essentially tell the game when/how to play your animation based on certain conditions. They are simply .xml files you can edit with the text-editor of your choice.
This part can involve a bit of trial and error and I suggest searching the vanilla games files to find an action similar to the one you&amp;rsquo;re making which you can adapt.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
